# Jimmy (Jieming) Hu

### Hobart TAS 7000

Mobile: 0493 260 301 | Email: jieming.hu@utas.edu.au / jiemingh213@gmail.com

Portfolio: <u>Jiemingh.me</u>

### **SUMMARY**

Recent graduate with a master's in Information Technology. Driven and energetic, I seek to work on professional projects that will exercise my technical skills, experience and teamwork for the benefit of the organization and team.

#### **SKILLS SUMMARY**

- Web Development: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, React.js, HTTP/HTTPS and APIs
- Software Development: Flutter, Swift, Kotlin, .NET Framework
- Database Management: SQL, PL/SQL, phpMyAdmin, MySQL
- Terminal Scripting: Linux
- Software Proficiencies: GitHub, VS Code, Android Studio, XCode, Firebase, VMs

# **EDUCATION AND QUALIFICATIONS**

# The University of Tasmania

February 2021- December 2022

Master of Information Communication Technology

• Tasmanian International Scholarship 2021

# **Sichuan University**

September 2016 - July 2020

Bachelor of Engineering (Electrical & Automation)

### **INDUSTRY EXPERIENCE**

#### **University of Tasmania (Technical Pool Program)**

August 2022 - NOW

**Casual Professional Developer** 

- Created and organized functions list of the application within schedule.
- Conducted front-end development of the application using Flutter in a cooperative team.
- Provided constructive suggestions for UI design by Norman's principles.
- Coordinated with project manager and client through Agile methodology during the development of the application.
- Prepared for group meetings with back-end team to ensure effective implementation of API.
- Updated weekly progress to project manager and client and exceeded their expectations.

# **MY IT Studio**

July 2022 – November 2022

**Intern Web Developer** 

- Learn the structural knowledge and React & Firebase stack skills required in the project.
- Constructed over 50 webpages using React.js following the UI design.
- Built correct connections with the database through the API provided by the Firebase framework.
- Coordinated with the senior developer and project manager for any issue raised during development.
- Re-organized and created web components and significantly improved working efficiency.
- Organized and planned tasks to complete the project within a time frame.

#### RECENT PROGRAM

# Water Can Profit 2022

A mobile application works as an economic calculator to enable whole-farm sensitivity analysis that accounts for factors including the price of water, irrigation layout, variable input costs and grain prices. By using Flutter, I built the main layout of the application including tabs, bottom navigators, app-bar, and details pages with interactive functions. I have cooperated with teammates from the back-end to build connections with the database by HTTP requests.

# 1 Plan 2022

A website provides professional business planning services for enterprises. Reports will be generated after completing queries of 5 sections. By using the React.js framework, I built the dashboard page, sidebar navigator, header navigator and over 50-page contents and all interactive functions for these components. I cooperated with the senior programmer to build connections with the database for webpages through the API provided by Firebase.

### **OTHERS**

CERTIFICATES: Migration Skill Assessment of Electronic Engineer (Skill Level 1)

LICENCE: Valid Overseas Driver's Licence

LANGUAGES: Fluent in English & Mandarin

INTERESTS: Basketball, Workout, Hiking and Guitar

### **REFEREES**

Referees are available upon request.